hey everyone welcome to another lesson
in this tosca automation course
today we are going to look at how tosca
provides us with different combination
methods
which can be triggered automatically so
till now we have been looking at how we
can manually create our combinations in
the test case design sheet but tosca
also provides us with different
automated methods through which it can
provide different number of combinations
and types of combinations
so let's see what are these different
methods
so there are basically four types of
methods through which toska combines the
data which you have created in your test
case design sheet you don't need to
manually create the combinations
okay
so going through all the different
methods to combine the data uh the first
method is all combinations as the name
suggests it
creates all the possible instance
combinations which are considered for
testing
and what this does is results in the
highest number of test cases okay
so whatever
instances you have created it will
create the combinations out of all those
instances so you can see the probability
would be much higher right so it will
cover each and every scenario
uh
orthogonal so this is the
type of combination where each instance
value will be used just once for each
combination
so this results in a very low number of
combinations right
the next is pairwise
it combines each pair of possible value
combinations for two attributes okay so
this will also not result in a higher
number of test cases
and then the linear expansion
it defines a straight through or happy
path combination okay
and it should always contain the highest
risk test cases
and this method is actually recommended
by trash centers because it provides you
uh with the right amount of test cases
not very high not very low okay
and this is also the most uh highest
test cases which would be beneficial for
your project or for your automation okay
so these are all the four combinations
now it depends on you on your project uh
what kind of requirement there is if you
want to test all the combinations you
can go with all combinations if you just
want to have just one instance
for
one combination then you can go for
orthogonal you can go for pairwise if
you want to do two possible uh i mean a
pair of
each possible value combination for two
attributes or you can go for linear
expansion which is also recommended by
dry centers
okay
so let's see this in action in our tosca
okay now i'm in my tosca instance where
we are at the testcase design sheet
earlier we had designed this regulation
test sheet
now just to remind you if you have not
seen this how we have designed this
regression test sheet
then please go to my earlier videos
where i have shown you how you can
create attributes and stances
and how you can assign instances to
different attributes right
so this is our test sheet and as you can
see
we have created some instances and we
have also assigned them
here so which is basically creating
different combinations of the data for
that particular attribute right now what
i have done is i've also added few more
instances to all the different
attributes right
so just show you how
toska can create different combinations
out of these attributes and instances
of data
right so i have added a few product
names some prices right so i have just
increased some instances for all the
different attributes
now as you can see there are just three
test cases right now so what i'm going
to do is i'm going to copy this
we're going to create some more
test sheets out of this right
um
so let me just
delete this let's copy this
and i'm going to paste it here
again i'm going to paste it here and
here
and here
right so i've got four different test
sheets i've just copied the original one
because i want to show you four
different combinations um the
combinational methods which tosca
provides okay
so let's go to this first test sheet now
how can we use the different combination
methods right so
there are different ways of doing that
either right click on the test sheet and
you can go to generate instances right
you will see
all the different um combination methods
which we have discussed
out of that
we are going to use the all combinations
here right
so um
if i select this all combinations now
tosca is going to generate combinations
out of all the different instances which
i have
created for all the different attributes
so there is a lot of competition and
combinations which will go on right it's
just mathematics
so
what it will do it will create all the
different instances and you will see
uh the number of instances grows right
and the number of test cases are now
previously there were only three test
cases
and now there are as you can see
it has got
almost 972
test cases right so
it is
it is a very high number of test cases
but if you really want to test all the
combinations of data this is the actual
uh number of test cases which you have
to test right
so it's actually not recommended unless
you have a lot of time uh to test all
your test cases right
because this is going to test um
everything right
um
now
you can fill this data uh there are also
different ways of doing that right
but this is going to create all the
combinations so the number of test cases
for all your test data okay
similarly if i go to test sheet 2 right
now there are three test cases but now
um i want to use a different
different type of combination okay so
i'm going to use the orthogonal
and as you can see in orthogonal we have
uh just got three more instances right
so we already had three and
uh tosca has added three more right so
that's those guys telling us that there
could be six test cases which could be
created out of uh the different
instances and uh the attributes
okay
now coming to third type of combination
so
the third type of combination is
pairwise and if i create pairwise um you
will see it has created little more test
cases than orthogonal
so there are 16 combinations which are
possible so there should be 16 test
cases okay
and coming to the last combination
method which is
the linear expansion also
it is recommended by tricentes
okay um so one thing um which i forgot
to mention earlier
is for linear expansion to work you have
to have a straight through
uh defined for your attributes okay
if you have not defined this then this
this combination will not be possible
okay because it requires all the
straight through instances okay so let's
go ahead and declare some
state through instances
okay so
what i'm going to do here is i'm going
to change
the new as the straight through instance
so
i'm going to say
toggle character and make this a
straight through instance okay
and then in process
i'm going to go to name
i'm going to make this a straight
through instance similarly for price
i will make this a straight through
instance
for quantity
let's make this
and for
shipping information free delivery
okay so now we have got a straight twin
stance for each of our attribute right
now what it is telling is these are the
most highest test cases or the highest
test flow
which could be used by the uh
customer right so this
is the straight through or the happy
path
basically okay
so let's go back and let's try again
let's go here and generate instances and
linear expansion okay so this time it
worked
um so as you can see this is
all the high risk test cases which
should be tested in
your this particular test sheet okay
and this uses all the straight through
instances or the happy path
got it
obviously uh it has taken
the names of those instances but you can
always change this names
okay
so there are around uh one two three
four five six seven eight nine ten
eleven twelve thirteen fourteen fifteen
sixteen test cases okay
so which is uh quite
similar to what we got in pairwise okay
so
this is how you can create
the different test case combinations out
of your attributes and instances
based on your project requirements okay
so as i said you can use any of these
combinations but attractions is already
recommends one combination so you should
probably go with that right so go with
the linear expansion and it will provide
you the right amount of test cases which
you require